<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20070518HP-BGBw6DDy8Ile-832-105137677</checksum>
<subtype>CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>UNCONTROLLED DIABETES MELLITUS</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.02</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>522.5,250.02,493.20,682.6,424.0,397.0,780.79,523.11,278.01,401.9,724.5,596.51,518.89,V12.59,V43.65,721.3,459.81,V58.67,V03.82,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


HISTORY:  This is a **AGE[in 70s]-year-old female patient who was admitted because of 
gingivitis and abscess gums.  The reason for the GU consult is urinary 
incontinence.  This patient has seen Dr. **NAME[VVV] before for urinary 
incontinence, and she had two bladder suspensions which helped in initial 
success, failed according to the patient.  The patient now is having 
mixed-type incontinence, has urgency as well as stress incontinence.  It 
appears; however, that the main component is urge incontinence.  The patient 
wears diapers.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Includes multiple medical problems including:

1.  Morbid obesity.
2.  Diabetes mellitus type 2.
3.  Bronchial asthma.
4.  Old stroke.
5.  Knee replacement.
6.  Chronic back pain.
7.  Hypertension.
8.  Osteoporosis.
9.  Degenerative joint disease.

MEDICATIONS:  
1.  Methocarbamol.
2.  Flexeril.
3.  Amitriptyline.
4.  Lyrica.
5.  Plavix.
6.  Indapamide.
7.  Nexium.
8.  Singulair.
9.  Glyburide.
10.  Prandin.
11.  Baby aspirin.

ALLERGIES:  None.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  An ex-smoker.  She does not drink.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  CONSTITUTIONAL:  The patient feels weak, and she has loss 
of appetite and decreased ability to ambulate.  The patient is morbidly 
obese.
RESPIRATORY:  No coughing.  No dyspnea.
CARDIOVASCULAR:  No chest pain.  No palpitations.
GI:  No change in bowel habits.
GU:  See history of present illness.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Pulse is 98 per minute, blood pressure 
is 140/77, and respiratory rate is 22 per minute.
HEAD, EYES, EARS, NOSE, AND THROAT:  Negative.
NECK:  Supple.
LUNGS:  Clear.
HEART:  Normal sinus rhythm.  No murmur.
ABDOMEN:  Soft and nontender.  Bowel sounds present.
EXTREMITIES:  The patient has redness of both lower extremities.
NEUROLOGICAL:  Deferred.

LABORATORY FINDINGS:  White blood count 10.7, hemoglobin 11.4, hematocrit 
34.9, serum creatinine 0.9, and blood glucose over 200.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  The patient appears to have severe overactive bladder 
syndrome.  We will check urine for infection.  We will start the patient on 
anticholinergics.


______________________________
**NAME[WWW M XXX], M.D.

HS Job # 808259 / 41124 / 
# **ID-NUM
D: **DATE[May 18 2007] 16:05
T: **DATE[May 19 2007] 21:13




</report_text>
</report>
