<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20070419HP-La8wdxTP4IxS-667-591741069</checksum>
<subtype>CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>BRAIN STEM INFARCT</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.02</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>250.02,599.0,781.2,845.00,E928.9,331.0,244.9,812.00,E888.9,380.4,041.4,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


CONSULTING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY ZZZ], D.O.

REASON FOR CONSULTATION: Rehabilitation evaluation following a fall and an old
bilateral lacunar infarct with ataxia.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: This is an **AGE[in 80s]-year-old female, with past medical
history significant for Alzheimer's dementia, hypertension, left internal
carotid artery stenosis, coronary artery disease, degenerative joint disease,
diabetes mellitus type 2, gastroesophageal reflux disease, and hiatal hernia,
who was admitted on **DATE[Apr 16 07] after a fall at home.  Family reports the patient
did not strike her head and there apparently was no loss of consciousness.  A
head CT upon admission to the Emergency Department revealed atrophy and chronic
small vessel ischemic changes, as well as small, old, lacunar infarcts in both
basal ganglia, as well as some sinus disease and mastoiditis.  A left foot
x-ray was performed and revealed degenerative changes.  A left ankle x-ray was
also performed and was negative for fracture.  A right shoulder fracture did
reveal an impacted surgical neck fracture, as well as degenerative joint
disease of the acromioclavicular joint.  Pelvic x-rays were performed and were
found to be negative for fracture.

The patient was evaluated by Dr. **NAME[SSS] from Orthopedics.  Apparently the right
humeral fracture is an old fracture and he recommended conservative measures
and cleared the patient for weightbearing as tolerated.  She is also cleared
for passive range-of-motion and active range-of-motion of the right shoulder.
The patient was also evaluated by Dr. **NAME[RRR] from ENT who did not feel that she
has an acute case of mastoiditis.  He recommended cerumen removal as an
outpatient.

Apparently the patient had been living with family members.  Her history is
obtained from the chart.  She is suffering from Alzheimer's dementia and is
unable to relay any history for me today.  She does complain of some left ankle
pain at this time, but otherwise has no other complaints.  She does move all 4
extremities and does follow some simple commands.

ALLERGIES:  AN ANTIBIOTIC.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS: Glyburide, Protonix, Synthroid, moexipril, triamterene
hydrochlorothiazide, donepezil, Theragran, and Namenda.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: Alzheimer's dementia, history of hypertension, old left
frontal infarct, left internal carotid artery stenosis 30%, coronary artery
disease, degenerative joint disease, chronic maxillary sinusitis, diabetes
mellitus type 2, gastroesophageal reflux disease, large hiatal hernia, mild
mitral regurgitation and tricuspid regurgitation and aortic regurgitation.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: Total abdominal hysterectomy in 1990 and bladder repair
in 1992.

FAMILY HISTORY: The patient's mother died at age **AGE[in 80s].  Father also died at age
**AGE[in 80s].  The patient's sister has arthritis.  She does have one brother who is
alive at the age of **AGE[in 70s].

SOCIAL HISTORY: She does not smoke or drink alcohol.  She apparently lives with
family members in a 1-story home with an unknown number of steps.

PAST LEVEL OF FUNCTIONING: Apparently the patient was able to ambulate fairly
independently.  I do not known if she used an assistive device.

CURRENT LEVEL OF FUNCTIONING: Yesterday with Physical Therapy the patient was
able to ambulate 360 feet with a rolling walker and supervision.  She
transferred supine to sit and sit to supine with independence.  She transferred
sit to stand with contact guard assistance.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: This is somewhat difficult to obtain as the patient is
demented.  She does complain of pain at the left ankle at this time.  She is
very hard of hearing.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:
GENERAL: This is a pleasant **AGE[in 80s]-year-old female who is awake, alert, hard of
hearing, but in no acute distress.  She is pleasantly confused.

VITAL SIGNS: Temperature is 98, pulse 61, respirations 18, blood pressure
98/48.

HEENT: Head is normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils are round and reactive to
light and accommodation.  Extraocular muscles are intact.

HEART: Regular rate and rhythm.

LUNGS: Clear to auscultation bilaterally.

ABDOMEN: Soft, nontender, nondistended, and bowel sounds are present.

EXTREMITIES: There is very mild erythema over the medial aspect of the left
ankle but otherwise there is no edema and no calf tenderness present.  She does
have very limited active range-of-motion at the right shoulder because of pain.


NEUROLOGIC: Cranial nerves II-XII appear to be grossly intact.  Sensation to
light touch is intact in all 4 extremities.  She does move all 4 extremities
spontaneously and follows some simple commands.  Plantar reflexes were
down-going bilaterally.  Muscle stretch reflexes were 1 over 4 at biceps,
triceps and patella and Achilles throughout.  Motor strength for grip
bilaterally was 4+.  Dorsiflexion and plantar flexion were also 4+/5
bilaterally.

IMPRESSION: This is an **AGE[in 80s]-year-old female who is status post a fall at home.
She suffers from ataxia and has a history of old bilateral lacunar infarcts and
an old right humeral fracture and a left ankle sprain.  She is currently
cleared for weightbearing as tolerated and is okay for passive and active
range-of-motion at the right shoulder.  She has been doing quite well with
physical therapy actually and walked 360 feet yesterday with a walker and
supervision.  At this point, she may not qualify for skilled PT and OT based on
her current level of function.  She probably would benefit from further
physical therapy and occupational therapy, perhaps as an outpatient or with
Home Care Services following her.  She would benefit from these services to
improve her balance, transfers and ambulation.  I will continue to follow this
patient with you.

Thank you very kindly for allowing me to participate in the care of this
patient.




______________________________
**NAME[YYY ZZZ], D.O.

D:   **DATE[Apr 19 2007]/ 7:40 A
T:   **DATE[Apr 19 2007]  8:54 A lz
     #**ACCESSION-NUMBER[1]/**ID-NUM


**CARBON-COPY


</report_text>
</report>
