<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20070517HP-d7fXjnacQ89X-489-1715008642</checksum>
<subtype>ADMISSION</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>SHEA MEDICAL CNTR/VISIT</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.80</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>250.80,428.0,707.15,403.91,412,443.9,731.8,735.4,784.0,414.01,530.81,730.27,V10.05,V45.82,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


**INSTITUTION
History &amp; Physical
Name: **NAME[AAA, BBB]
Acct #: **ID-NUM
MRN: **ID-NUM
Admitted: **DATE[May 17 2007]
Dict: **NAME[WWW, VVV]
Attend: **NAME[ZZZ, YYY]
Admission history and physical.  Date of evaluation, **DATE[May 17 2007].  
Clinical location, **INSTITUTION.
**INSTITUTION:  Right second toe osteomyelitis and 
diabetic foot ulcer.
I have personally seen and examined the patient.  Please consider my notes 
linked to the resident's.  I have reviewed her case with Dr. **NAME[UUU 
TTT], and **NAME[M] am in agreement with the resident's admission history and 
physical.
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, this is a **AGE[in 70s]-year-old African American 
female well known to me from my outpatient setting.  She has a complicated 
past medical history that includes established coronary artery disease for 
which medical management has been implicated, multiple MIs, stent placement, 
refractory blood pressure, on 4 to 5 antihypertensives.  Suboptimally 
controlled insulin-requiring diabetes mellitus.  She had been in her usual 
state of health until **DATE[Feb 2007] when she noticed a discoloration in her 
right second toe.  She was evaluated for this in the office, and there was no 
obvious edema or certainly no pain in the area.  There was a small break in 
the skin by **DATE[Apr 2007] without evidence of erythema.  It was very 
superficial.  It was thought that it would heal.  She has got known 
peripheral vascular disease.  Despite conservative treatment, the right 
second toe has grown much larger in size.  It became painful 4 days ago.  The 
nail itself fell off approximately 3 to 4 weeks ago, and she started to 
notice a growing ulceration.  It has a burning or stinging quality.  She is 
not on anything to make the pain better.  It is substantially worse with 
walking and will actually bleed.  She has not noted fever or chills or 
systemic complaints.  She still remains dizzy and is having difficulty with 
gait disturbance.  Recent MRI/MRA showed no evidence of cerebrovascular 
disease that could be contributing to her dizziness.
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  
1.  Coronary artery disease, followed by Dr. **NAME[SSS].
2.  Resistant or difficult to control hypertension.
3.  Renal insufficiency.
4.  Diabetes mellitus, insulin requiring.
5.  Osteomyelitis of the left great toe.
6.  Colon cancer diagnosed in **DATE[Jan 2006], status post colostomy and then 
colostomy reversal.
7.  Appendectomy.
8.  History of slightly reduced ejection fraction, longstanding diastolic 
dysfunction.
9.  Cholecystectomy.
ALLERGIES:  PENICILLIN WHICH CAUSES HIVES.
MEDICATIONS:  Currently include:
1.  Prandin 1 mg with meals.
2.  Vytorin **DATE[Feb 21] mg daily.
3.  Vasotec 20 mg twice daily.
4.  Protonix 40 mg daily.
5.  Prandin 1 mg with meals.
6.  Plavix 75 mg daily.
7.  Magnesium oxide 400 mg daily.
8.  Lasix 40 to 60 mg daily depending on fluid and volume status.
9.  Lantus insulin.
10.  Imdur 60 mg extended release.
11.  Catapres patch TTS-3.
12.  Atenolol 100 mg twice daily.
13.  Aspirin 81 mg daily.
14.  Docusate b.i.d. 100 mg.
15.  K-Dur 20 mEq daily.
SOCIAL HISTORY:  She lives with her daughter.  She is fairly functional, 
cognitively intact.  No tobacco, no alcohol use.
FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She is discouraged by the vitiligo or hypopigmentation 
she has developed over the right side of her face.  She attributes this to 
antibiotics.  She has had no chest discomfort, no shortness of breath.  No 
nausea, no gastrointestinal complaints.  She occasionally gets pain at the 
surgical site where her colostomy takedown was, but this has been stable 
through time.  Remainder of review of systems is negative.
CLINICAL EXAM:  Her blood pressure here is 214/107, weight is stable.  A 
tired, fatigued-appearing, elderly African American female in no acute 
distress.  Depressed about the impending admission to the hospital.  Her 
pupils react.  Her sclerae are injected.  Her oropharynx is clear.  Neck is 
supple.  Heart is regular.  There is an S4 present and a systolic murmur.  
Her carotid upstrokes are delayed.  She has evidence of hypopigmentation on 
the right side of her face.  It is patchy, and there are several discrete 
macules extending to the maxillary area.  Abdomen is soft.  There are 
normoactive bowel sounds.  Her extremities have 1+ edema at the calves.  She 
does have evidence of marked edema and discoloration of the right second toe. 
There is a clawtoe deformity there.  There is an ulcer at the tip of the 
digit consistent with ischemic ulceration, possibly from poor blood supply.  
Her peripheral pulse is weak but palpable in the dorsalis pedis range.  
Posterior tibial is unobtainable.  There is slight warmth over the forefoot.
IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  
1.  Right second digit diabetic foot ulcer.  Likely arterial ischemia given 
the degree of pain that she is currently having.  Needs to have a semi-urgent 
evaluation by vascular surgery.  We discussed the option of amputation, and 
she is less than satisfied with this as a treatment modality.  We will have 
Dr. **NAME[RRR] evaluate her as soon as possible to consider IV antibiotic therapy. 
We will have a PICC line placed and proceed with the next management 
decision.
2.  Difficult to control hypertension.  Blood pressure is once again quite 
high here despite the multidrug regimen that she is on.  We will continue to 
monitor in the inpatient setting.  Daughter reports it is normal and have a 
24-hour monitor by Dr. **NAME[SSS]'s office that shows markedly improved values 
over the current ones, so we will continue to monitor, do not change drug 
therapy at this time.
3.  Gastroesophageal reflux disease.  Continue Prilosec.
4.  Other medical issues stable including diabetes mellitus.  Continue 
outpatient medications.  Her last hemoglobin A1c was 8.7.  We have tried 
titrating her medications, and we have run into the problems of hypoglycemia. 
Keep her on her baseline Lantus, Prandin, and adjust insulin basally as 
necessary during the inpatient stay.
______________________________
**NAME[VVV WWW], MD
HS Job # 786366 / 33115 / 
SHY # **ID-NUM
D: **DATE[May 17 2007] 18:10
T: **DATE[May 17 2007] 18:13

**CARBON-COPY


</report_text>
</report>
