<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20070708HP-2ahUiPexicpn-848-1860153850</checksum>
<subtype>ENDO CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>DKA</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.10</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>584.9,710.0,437.4,403.91,284.8,250.10,791.0,583.81,795.79,E932.0,272.4,593.9,278.00,724.2,715.90,293.9,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


 
**INSTITUTION
ENDOCRINE
CONSULTATION
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB M]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY M ZZZ]
CONSULTING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[WWW XXX], M.D.
ADMISSION DATE:  **DATE[Jul 03 2007]
DATE OF CONSULTATION:  
REASON FOR CONSULT:
New onset diabetes mellitus.
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: 
Mr. **NAME[AAA] is a **AGE[in 40s]-year-old, white male with systemic lupus erythematosus and 
lupus nephritis who presented to **INSTITUTION with polydipsia, polyuria and 
blood glucose in the 900s after being started on prednisone for the last 
month for lupus flare.  Anion gap was 17, but there were no urine ketones, 
but he was admitted to the MICU for treatment of DKA.  Endocrine was 
consulted for new onset diabetes, possibly prednisone induced. 
About a month ago, the patient had laboratory work drawn by Dr. **NAME[TTT] who 
is his rheumatologist and he also had a funny taste in the back of his mouth 
which is what he gets with his lupus flares.  He had a 24 hour urine done 
which showed 10 grams of protein, so his CellCept was increased from 500 to 
1500 b.i.d. and he was started on prednisone 16 mg once a day with plans to 
taper after one month of treatment.  Over the last few weeks, the patient had 
been drinking four to five gallons of fluid a day and also had polyuria where 
he would get up to urinate every 15 to 30 minutes.  He also had orthostatic 
dizziness.  No nausea, vomiting, no shortness of breath, chest pain, vision 
changes or headache. 
On admission, the patient was treated with IV fluids and an insulin drip and 
his anion gap closed in six hours.  Potassium went from 6.1 to 4.7, 
creatinine from 2.0 to 1.5 which is his baseline.  There are no ketones 
present in the urine.  Urine glucose was 1000 and protein was 30.  Blood 
glucose went from 900 to 400.  The patient's polydipsia and polyuria have 
improved.   
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: 
No fevers or chills.  No leg edema.  No diarrhea or constipation.  No burning 
on urination.  Decreased appetite, but this is improving. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:
1) Systemic lupus erythematosus diagnosed in 2002, being followed by Dr. 
**NAME[TTT].  Manifestations include arthritis, renal, CNS and cutaneous.  The 
patient is also anticardiolipin antibody positive. 
2) Hyperlipidemia.
3) Hypertension.
4) Tumor cerebri in remission.
SOCIAL HISTORY: 
Positive for tobacco and marijuana.  No alcohol or IV drugs.
FAMILY HISTORY:
Grandmother with diabetes.
ALLERGIES:
NONE KNOWN.
HOME MEDICATIONS:
1) CellCept 1500 mg p.o. b.i.d. 
2) Prednisone 60 mg p.o. daily.
3) Diovan 160 mg p.o. daily.
4) Atenolol 25 mg p.o. daily.
5) Coumadin 5 mg p.o. daily.
6) Lasix.
INPATIENT MEDICATIONS include home medications except for Lasix which has 
been held.  Also he is on Protonix 40 mg p.o. b.i.d., insulin drip and normal 
saline IV fluids at 100 cc per hour. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: 
VITALS:  Temperature 36.1, blood pressure 154/73, pulse 79, respirations 20, 
O2 saturations 94% on room air.  Weight is 122 kg. 
GENERAL:  No apparent distress, alert and oriented times three.
HEENT:  No cervical lymphadenopathy.  Oropharynx clear.
CARDIOVASCULAR:  Regular rate and rhythm.  No murmurs, rubs, or gallops.
PULMONARY:  Clear to auscultation.  No wheezing, rales or rhonchi.
ABDOMEN:  Soft, obese, nontender, nondistended, bowel sounds present.
EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.
SKIN:  No malar rash or any other lesions.
NEUROLOGIC:  Pupils equal and reactive.  Extraocular movements intact.  
Nonfocal. 
LABORATORY DATA: 
Potassium was 6.1, now 5.2, sodium was 123, corrected for glucose was 128, 
now it is 132.  Bicarb was 20 and now is 16, creatinine was 2.0, now is 1.5.  
Blood glucose was 900, now is 400.  Anion gap was 17 and is now 9.0.  White 
count is 11.3.  Hemoglobin is 15.7.  Urine has no ketones, glucose is 1000, 
leukocyte esterase and nitrates are absent, protein is 30. 
24-hour urine **DATE[May 29] showed 10.2 grams of protein.  Chest x-ray shows no 
acute process. 
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN: 
Mr. **NAME[AAA] is a **AGE[in 40s]-year-old, white male with SLE, a lupus nephritis on 
prednisone for the last month, presenting with hyperosmolar hyperglycemia.  
The absence of ketones in a relatively small, although increased anion gap, 
and lack of any other symptoms besides polyuria, makes DKA an unlikely 
diagnosis.  This patient has steroid-induced diabetes mellitus at the very 
least which may or may not resolve after the prednisone is discontinued.  As 
the patient has lupus nephritis and renal insufficiency at baseline, oral 
hypoglycemic options are limited.  The best option at this point would be to 
start the patient on subcu insulin. 
1) Check hemoglobin A1c.
2) The patient is not currently on a statin despite having an elevated 
cholesterol.  Check LFTs and consider starting Vytoran. 
3) Blood pressure goal in diabetics is 130/80.  The patient currently is not 
meeting this goal and his blood pressure medications will need to be adjusted 
accordingly. 
4) Nutrition and diabetic education consult.
5) Start Lantus 25 units subcu q.h.s. (bedtime) and Humalog 8 units with 
meals three times a day.  Humalog sliding scale insulin low dose. 
6) Will discuss with attending.
 
___________________________________
**NAME[SSS RRR], M.D.
 
Dictator:  **NAME[WWW XXX], M.D.
CT/pap
D:  **DATE[Jul 08 2007] 22:20:31
T:  **DATE[Jul 10 2007] 10:27:54
R:  **DATE[Jul 10 2007] 10:27:54/pap
Job ID:  337973/**ID-NUM
Cc:
 
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[XXX, QQQ] ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[SSS RRR]  **DATE[Aug 06 2007] 09:45:26 AM
 



</report_text>
</report>
