<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20071210HP-huwFAVL6OXpk-848-252052630</checksum>
<subtype>ENDO CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>DIABETES</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.03</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>250.03,303.90,305.60,V58.67,311,296.80,272.4,369.60,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


 
**INSTITUTION
ENDOCRINE
CONSULTATION
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY M ZZZ]
CONSULTING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[RRR QQQ], M.D.
ADMISSION DATE:  **DATE[Dec 08 2007]
DATE OF CONSULTATION:  **DATE[Dec 10 07]
REASON FOR CONSULTATION:
Diabetes management.
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:
Mr. **NAME[AAA] is a pleasant **AGE[in 30s]-year-old gentleman with a strong history of type 2 
diabetes, diagnosed with diabetes in 2002 that has been poorly controlled.  
He was admitted to **INSTITUTION on **DATE[Dec 02] with diabetic 
ketoacidosis and then transferred here on **DATE[Dec 08] for further management 
of his diabetes.  It is unclear if he has type 1 or type 2 diabetes.  He 
states that he was diagnosed with diabetes when he presented for a 
psychiatric admission in 2002 and has been on insulin ever since.  He 
initially was on 70/30, 30 to 45 units twice daily with a sliding scale and 
then was switched to Lantus 100 units subcu q. afternoon with a Regular 
sliding scale four times per day approximately one month ago.  He only uses 
the sliding scale if his blood glucose is greater than 200.  His Lantus was 
then reduced to 90 units three weeks ago but he was still having morning 
hypoglycemia into the 50s.  He checks his blood glucose four times per day at 
home with fasting blood glucoses being reportedly between 50 to 120, 
lunchtime values being 200 and 250, dinnertime values being between 200 and 
250 and bedtime values being between 180 and 250.  He often snacks to prevent 
hypoglycemia and eats a large dinner to compensation for hypoglycemia as 
well.   
At the outside hospital, his regimen was switched to Lantus 75 units subcu 
q.a.m. with NovoLog 5 units subcu q.a.c. and a low to moderate dose sliding 
scale with a rather erratic control.  He was transferred here, as I 
mentioned, and has had erratic control of his blood glucose with both 
hypoglycemia and hyperglycemia.   
He reports a history of peripheral neuropathy but denies nephropathy or 
retinopathy.  He has been hospitalized three times in the last one-and-a-half 
months with high blood glucose. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:
1. Diabetes mellitus as per HPI.
2. Polysubstance abuse.
3. Chronic back pain.
4. Depression.
5. Bipolar disorder.
6. Remote motor vehicle accident with left eye blindness.
7. Hyperlipidemia.
MEDICATIONS:
1. Lantus 75 units subcu q.a.m. 
2. NovoLog 5 units subcu q.a.c.
3. NovoLog moderate dose sliding scale q. six hours.
4. Lyrica 50 mg p.o. t.i.d. 
5. Percocet.
ALLERGIES:  NO KNOWN DRUG ALLERGIES.
SOCIAL HISTORY:  
He lives alone and is single.  He denies current drug use but previously used 
marijuana and cocaine.  He quit smoking two months ago and smoked 
approximately two packs per day on and off for three years.  He has a history 
of alcohol abuse but has cut back and now drinks only one to two drinks per 
week.  Prior, he was drinking a case of beer per day.   
FAMILY HISTORY: 
His mother, father, two uncles and multiple cousins have type 2 diabetes.  
His maternal uncle, mother and maternal grandmother have a history of 
coronary artery disease with his mother dying at age **AGE[in 40s] from a myocardial 
infarction.   
The same maternal uncle also has a history of hyperlipidemia.  Another 
maternal uncle has a history of an unknown type of cancer. 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:
Review of systems is as per HPI.  In addition, he reports his last eye exam 
was approximately one year ago.  He has pain, paresthesias and numbness in 
bilateral lower extremities.  Diffuse pain.  Dysuria.  Occasional chest pain 
unrelated to activity.  The remainder of the systems is negative. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:
General:  This is a pleasant male in no acute distress.  
Psychiatric:  Currently normal judgement, mood, insight and affect.
Vital signs:  Pulse 66, blood pressure 108/70, temperature 36.3.
Eyes:  The left pupil is 4 mm and nonreactive.  The right pupil is 3 mm and 
reactive.  Extraocular movements intact.  Sclerae anicteric.   
E.N.T.:  Oropharynx is clear with moist mucous membranes.
Neck:  Supple.  No thyromegaly or masses.
Lymph nodes:  No cervical, supraclavicular, suboccipital lymphadenopathy.
Cardiovascular:  Regular rate and rhythm with no murmurs, rubs or gallops.
Lungs:  Clear to auscultation bilaterally with normal expansion.
Abdomen:  Positive bowel sounds; soft, nontender, nondistended.  There is 
some suprapubic tenderness in the midline scar extending from below the 
sternum to the lower abdomen.   
Neurologic:  The patient is alert and oriented times three.  Reflexes 1+.  
Diminished monofilament with hyperesthesia. 
Skin:  Warm and dry.  No ulcers.
DATA:
I reviewed the patient's paper and electronic medical chart as summarized 
above. 
LABORATORY DATA: 
At **PLACE, his initial glucose was 353 with an anion gap of 21.  He had a 
normal ALT, AST and troponin.  Urine had 1,000 glucose and positive ketones.  
His creatinine was 1.2.  His cholesterol was 220 with an HDL of 28 and 
triglycerides 1,185.  His glucoses were extremely variable with both 
hypoglycemia and hyperglycemia. 
Here, his hemoglobin A1C was found to be 10.7.  His creatinine is 0.8.  His 
urinalysis revealed only 1,000 of glucose.  His blood glucoses ranged between 
56 and 316. 
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN: 
This is a **AGE[in 30s]-year-old gentleman with diabetes mellitus (unclear type), 
hyperlipidemia and chronic pain.  He was admitted with resolved diabetic 
ketoacidosis and erratic glycemic control.   
1.  Diabetes mellitus.  His type of diabetes is unclear.  I neglected to 
mention above but he is very lean and given his history of diabetic 
ketoacidosis and insulin use since the time of diagnosis, it may be type 1.  
He is currently on a disproportionate amount of basal insulin compared to 
prandial insulin.   
We would recommend changing his insulin regimen to Lantus 60 units subcu 
q.a.m., continuing Humalog  5 units subcu q.a.c., and changing his sliding 
scale to low dose.  He likely will need much more prandial insulin; however, 
we will begin at a low dose.  It is very difficult with limited information 
to determine what his actual requirements will be and he may be discharged 
tomorrow.  I also would recommend starting aspirin 81 mg per day, checking a 
urine microalbumin to creatinine ratio and having the patient scheduled an 
outpatient eye exam.  He should follow up with an endocrinologist within one 
to two weeks after discharge. 
2.  Hypertriglyceridemia.  This is likely related to poor glycemic control.  
This should be repeated as an outpatient. 
3.  Peripheral neuropathy.  Continue Lyrica.
4.  Atypical chest pain.  He tells me that he has already attempted a 
treadmill test but was unable to complete the test due to pain.  I would 
recommend a nuclear stress test as an outpatient. 
Thank you for allowing us to participate in this patient's care.  The patient 
was seen with the Attending, Dr. **NAME[RRR  
PPP].  
       
___________________________________
**NAME[RRR PPP], M.D.
Attending Physician 
 
____________________________________ 
**NAME[WWW M. XXX], M.D.
Endocrinology Fellow
Dictator:  **NAME[WWW M. XXX], M.D.
**INITIALS
D:  **DATE[Dec 13 2007] 11:49:34
T:  **DATE[Dec 14 2007] 09:05:24
R:  **DATE[Dec 14 2007] 09:05:24/lek
Job ID:  345289/**ID-NUM
 
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[XXX], MD-**NAME[WWW M]. ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[RRR PPP]  **DATE[Jan 06 2008] 09:15:19 AM
 



</report_text>
</report>
