<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20070912HP-bkKPPG8Cj4Kd-848-157413249</checksum>
<subtype>GIM HP</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>DKA</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.10</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>250.13,276.51,276.2,008.8,285.9,536.3,401.9,621.9,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


 
**INSTITUTION
GENERAL MEDICINE
HISTORY AND PHYSICAL EXAMINATION
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB M]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY]  **NAME[ZZZ]
ADMISSION DATE:  **DATE[Sep 12 2007]
CHIEF COMPLAINT:  
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  
This is a **AGE[in 50s]-year-old female with a history of insulin-dependent diabetes 
mellitus, type 1 with a history of being noncompliant with doctors' visits 
and noncompliance with taking her blood pressure and diabetes medication.  
She was complaining of nausea yesterday times one day with vomiting and fever 
and diarrhea.  She was hyperglycemic and initially went to the emergency 
department on **DATE[Sep 09 2007] and was treated with IV fluids and insulin and went 
home.  She came back yesterday with more nausea and vomiting and blood sugar 
in excess of 600 accompanied by metabolic acidosis.  She was admitted to the 
intensive care unit and was treated with IV fluids and IV insulin.  Her anion 
gap metabolic acidosis has resolved and her glucoses are down into the 100 
range.  Currently, she denies fevers, chills, sweats, dizziness, nausea, 
vomiting, diarrhea, abdominal pain.  She complains of sternal chest 
discomfort with meals, not with exertion.  No shortness of breath.  Also 
complains of mid to low bilateral paraspinal back discomfort.   
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:
Notable for carpal tunnel syndrome and is as above and otherwise negative. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:
Insulin-dependent diabetes, hypertension, carpal tunnel syndrome.
SOCIAL HISTORY:
Positive cigarette use, occasional alcohol use.  Denies significant alcohol 
use.  Denies drug use.   
FAMILY HISTORY:
Positive for diabetes.  
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:
VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature is 36.9, blood pressure 160/80, pulse 96, 
respiratory rate 16. 
GENERAL:  Mentation normal.  
HEENT:  Sclerae white.  Conjunctivae pink.  Moist mucosa.  No oral lesions.  
NECK:  Supple.  No adenopathy, goiter, JVD, or bruits.
LUNGS:  Clear without wheeze, rhonchi, rales.
HEART:  S1 and S2 regular rate and rhythm.  No murmurs, rubs, or gallops. 
ABDOMEN:  Soft and nontender.  No organomegaly.  
EXTREMITIES:  No cyanosis, clubbing, or edema.
DATA:
Chest x-ray shows no infiltrates.  CT scan of the abdomen and pelvis shows no 
acute inflammatory process.  Nonobstructing left renal calculi.  Tox screen 
was negative.  Troponins are negative.   
EKG INTERPRETATION: 
EKG shows normal sinus rhythm with voltage criteria for left ventricular 
hypertrophy.  No ischemic changes.   
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:
Diabetic ketoacidosis, probably precipitated by viral syndrome, proved.  
Continue Lantus insulin currently at 26 units daily.  Lispro insulin with 
meals and at bedtime 8 units and sliding scale insulin.  Continue lisinopril 
and hydrochlorothiazide for hypertension.  I discussed the case with Dr. 
**NAME[XXX] from the CCM team. She is stable to be transferred to the floor 
today.   
 
___________________________________
**NAME[YYY ZZZ], M.D.
 
Dictator:  **NAME[YYY ZZZ], M.D.
AS/crl
D:  **DATE[Sep 13 2007] 11:15:31
T:  **DATE[Sep 14 2007] 08:25:36
R:  **DATE[Sep 14 2007] 08:25:36/crl
Job ID:  345241/**ID-NUM
 
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[ZZZ, WWW] ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[YYY ZZZ]  **DATE[Sep 22 2007] 09:12:22 PM
 



</report_text>
</report>
