<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20071022HP-5u0BSAb362uG-848-793012707</checksum>
<subtype>GIM HP</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>DKA TYPE 2</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.10</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>250.10,493.90,726.90,V15.81,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


 
 
**INSTITUTION
GENERAL MEDICINE
HISTORY AND PHYSICAL EXAMINATION
 
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB M]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY]  **NAME[ZZZ]
ADMISSION DATE:  **DATE[Oct 22 2007]
 
 
DATE OF SERVICE:  **DATE[Oct 23 2007]
 
This is a history and physical for attending, please see Dr. **NAME[XXX]'s note for 
detail of the patient's presentation and plan.  I agree with plan outlined 
in his note and the case was discussed with him. I have personally seen and
examined the patient.
 
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  
 
In brief, this a **AGE[in teens]-year-old woman who was admitted with DKA.  **NAME[BBB], 
unfortunately, has had four to five episodes of DKA over the last year
secondary to medication noncompliance and some  social issues going on in her
house.  Over the last three or four days, she  has had a viral illness and been
not consistent about taking her medications. 
 This was also complicated by some conflict with her parents and she left or
was either kicked out of her house the day of her admission.  She was
complaining  of some abdominal pain and some runny nose and cough, but
otherwise denies  fevers, chills, diarrhea, chest pain, palpitations,
lightheadedness, syncope,  or presyncope.  
 
PAST MEDICAL/SURGICAL HISTORY:  
 
Her past medical history is notable for type 1 diabetes, asthma, and in 
**DATE[Jun] of 2006 she had an MVA leading to an L1 compression fracture. 
 
ALLERGIES:
 
SHE IS ALLERGIC TO PENICILLIN AND AMOXICILLIN.
 
MEDICATIONS:  
 
Her medications on presentation are Lantus 66 units at bedtime and NovoLog 30 
units with each meal, and Ultram, though her compliance with these is a 
little unclear.   
 
SOCIAL HISTORY:  
 
She just moved into a friend's place where she is being allowed to occupy a 
room.  She is not paying rent.  She works as clerical work.  She denies any 
smoking, drinking, or alcohol use.  She is sexually active with a boyfriend 
and she has had several sexual partners in the last year.  She says she is 
generally good about using protection. 
 
FAMILY HISTORY:  
 
The family history is notable for hypertension and thyroid disease.
 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  
 
Her review of systems was otherwise negative except for the viral symptoms of 
runny nose and cough that I noted above.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  
 
Her vital signs on my examination were blood pressure was 126/70, heart rate 
was around 120, respirations were 20, she was afebrile, and she was sating 
100% on room air.  She was a tired-appearing young woman in no acute 
distress, occasionally sniffling her nose.  Her oropharynx was clear.  She 
had no sinus tenderness.  She had no nuchal rigidity.  Lungs were clear to 
auscultation.  No wheeze was appreciated.  She was tachy, no murmurs were 
noted.  Her abdomen was soft. She had no hepatosplenomegaly and no pain.  Her 
extremities were warm and well perfused.  She had no obvious rash.  Her 
strength was grossly intact.   
 
LABORATORY RESULTS:  
 
Her most recent laboratory work from 1:30 on **DATE[Oct 23 2007] showed an anion gap 
of 7 with a bicarb of 21.  Her latest glucoses were 191, 193, and 292.  Her 
CBC was within normal limits except for a low neutrophil count, but high 
bands of 8.   
 
 
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  
 
This is a **AGE[in teens]-year-old young woman admitted for DKA secondary to noncompliance 
and a recent viral illness complicated by a difficult social situation.   
 
1. Her DKA.  She has been transitioned from an insulin drip to her first dose 
of Lantus this afternoon.  We will stop her D5 half normal saline solution 
and simply follow her sugars closely through the course of the day and also 
follow her laboratory studies to ensure that her gap does not return and her 
glucoses are reasonably well controlled.   
 
2. She has had some new sexual partners.  There has been some concern about 
her protection.  This was discussed with her and we will proceed with some 
STD testing just to make sure.  She did have a urine pregnancy test in the ED 
that was negative. 
 
3. The most significant issue with **NAME[BBB] obviously is her social situation
amd how  to prevent another one of these episodes of DKA.  We have had Social
Work and  Medical Assistance come and see if she can apply for and receive
Medicaid in  an effort to help her with compliance with her medications.  Will
also work  with the social worker in the **INSTITUTION to see what other
support we  can provide **NAME[BBB] as she makes this transition from her home to
this new  living situation.  It has obviously been stressed to **NAME[BBB] that
continued  noncompliance will lead to DKA which she is well aware.   
 
 
___________________________________
**NAME[YYY]  **NAME[ZZZ]
 
 
 
 
Dictator:  **NAME[YYY ZZZ], M.D.
 
AM/klf
 
D:  **DATE[Oct 23 2007] 15:23:06
T:  **DATE[Oct 23 2007] 21:08:25
R:  **DATE[Oct 23 2007] 21:08:25/klf
 
Job ID:  358551/**ID-NUM
 
Cc:
 
 
 
 
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[ZZZ, WWW] ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[YYY ZZZ]  **DATE[Nov 20 2007] 09:51:13 AM
 



</report_text>
</report>
