<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<report>
<checksum>20070811HP-RBxAT+GYNvV9-489-470818067</checksum>
<subtype>ADMISSION</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>HYPEROSMALOR HYPERGLYCEMIA</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>250.23</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>250.23,496,425.4,272.4,401.9,V45.81,729.82,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time/>
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


**INSTITUTION
History &amp; Physical
Name: **NAME[AAA, BBB]
Acct #: **ID-NUM
MRN: **ID-NUM
Admitted: **DATE[Aug 11 2007]
Dict: **NAME[WWW, VVV]
Attend: **NAME[WWW, VVV]
This **AGE[in 50s]-year-old is being admitted for hyperosmolar state with hyperglycemia. 
This patient was seen in the office today for a followup visit.  He reported 
that blood sugars have all been over 400 and that today's blood sugar was 
450.  He had recently seen Endocrinology who increased the Lantus from 60 
units to 65 units and also began Humalog before each meal with a sliding 
scale starting at 8 before breakfast and lunch and then 12 before dinner.  
The patient, according the sliding scale, increased this to 20 units t.i.d. 
before each meal and has noted no lowering of blood sugars.  The patient said 
that he is rotating sides.  His last hemoglobin A1c was 15.
The patient is also reporting that his hands are cramping up.  This happens a 
couples of times a week.  It also occurs in his right leg and works his hands 
to get this to go away.
The patient also reports that he does have a upper respiratory infection for 
the past few days.
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for triple coronary artery bypass grafting 
with cardiomyopathy secondary to ischemic heart disease and poor LV function. 
His cardiologist is Dr. **NAME[UUU].  He also has a past history of smoking 
and alcoholism.  He also has a history of hyperlipidemia and hypertension.
SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient is a smoker as above.  He is currently not 
working.
FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As above.  All remaining systems negative.
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Blood pressure is 116/77.  Weight is 210.  Previous 
weight was 203.  The skin is warm and dry.  Neck:  There is no jugular venous 
distention.  The hepatojugular reflex is negative.  Lungs are clear to 
percussion and auscultation.  Heart:  Tachycardia with no murmur or gallop.  
Abdomen:  Soft and nontender.  Extremities:  Without edema.
LABORATORY VALUES:  Per chart, the glucose is 908.  Serum sodium 125, 
corrected is 137.  Bicarbonate is 17.
ASSESSMENT:  
1.  Hyperosmolar hyperglycemia, possible diabetic ketoacidosis.  This patient 
will be admitted.  Insulin drip will be used at first, but it is important 
that his baseline insulin be given as well.  This hospitalization will also 
be used to explore why he has been so resistant.  One possibility of course 
is that he is not taking his insulin, and this would become quickly evident 
in the hospital.  Endocrinology should be consulted.  Dr. **NAME[TTT SSS] 
should be consulted.
2.  Cardiomyopathy:  This patient needs echocardiogram as this has not been 
done in at least 1 year.  We need to consider ACE inhibitor.  His blood 
pressure is on the low side, and his creatinine is elevated.
3.  Cramping of the hands.  We should check magnesium and calcium and clear.  
This might be related to the current metabolic abnormalities.
4.  Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.  The patient is using albuterol, 
but we should probably start Combivent.
5.  Chronic renal insufficiency:  Last creatinine was 1.3.  We will check 
this again while in the hospital.
______________________________
**NAME[VVV M WWW], MD
HS Job # 657786 / 38808 / 
SHY # **ID-NUM
D: **DATE[Aug 11 2007] 16:05
T: **DATE[Aug 11 2007] 16:13

**CARBON-COPY


</report_text>
</report>
